# Nick Alkaff (Mr)

Flat 1 Hamilton Court, 38 Draycott Avenue, Harrow, Middlesex HA3 0BU Telephone: +44 (0) 7956 306337 E-mail: rednick09@gmail.com

# **Personal Profile**

A hard worker with a desire to assist colleagues and individuals in a friendly, helpful and reliable manner. Underlined by an employment history of providing excellent and professional customer service.

My work experience is very broad due to variety of positions that I have held in different working environments. However I am an established IT Professional with rounded experience of system support including installations, network maintenance, applications support and data analysis.

I am friendly, approachable and always willing to take full ownership of issues, communicating findings to all levels at all times.

A keen problem solver, logical and methodical in approach and pride myself at getting the job done. I work well on my own or as a team and value skill sharing and to pool ideas.

# **Key skills and attributes**

- Windows Server 2003, 2008 R2 and 2012
- VMWare / VSphere
- Microsoft Outlook and Exchange
- Active Directory
- Print server and configuring secure printing on Kyocera software
- Operating Systems (Windows 9x / 2000 / XP / Vista / 7, 8 and 10)
- Installations, maintenance, repairs (desktops / laptops / printers / networks / mobile devices)
- Network maintenance (WANs, LANs, VPN, DNS, DHCP, TCP/IP, Avaya WI-FI access points) troubleshooting and diagnostics
- · Configuring and implementation of ghost builds (Norton Ghost)
- Excellent knowledge of MS Office / Outlook / Movie Maker
- Remote support tools such as VNC Viewer, Log Me In and Remote Desktop Connection
- Efficient trouble shooter and fast learner
- Superb customer service skills and telephone manner

# **Work Experience**

Customer Services (Temp)
Transport Exchange Group

July 2019 - Present

• Receiving calls from members of the Exchange regarding subscriptions, product support, and complaints • Assuring members are happy with services provided and advising with any queries • Providing telephone training of products • Technical support of members webpage portal and mobile app

### Full time Carer (Gap in employment)

May 2017 - July 2019

Since being made redundant from my previous employer, I took responsibility of taking care for my Mother who had been diagnosed with Cancer. After a year she sadly passed and I have since been taking care of my elderly Father. However other family members are now able to help with caring responsibilities, I am now in a position to return to work.

## IT Technician (2nd / 3rd Line)

Partnerships In Care

October 2015 - May 2017

• Supporting over 8000 users using the Service Desk Plus (Sysaid) in accordance with SLAs • Installing and troubleshooting Windows 8, 7, XP, Microsoft Office • Re-imaging PCs using Smart Deploy • Troubleshooting network related issues such as DNS, DHCP, TCP/ IP, Avaya Wi-Fi access points and patching network cables • Maintaining Windows Server 2003, 2008 R2, 2012 • Adding, removing users, setting passwords and file permissions on Active Directory and AD Manager Plus • Microsoft Outlook and Exchange • Installing and configuring secure printing on Kyocera printers • Remote desktop support via Ultra VNC, Team Viewer or Sysaid • Configuration and support of Windows Lumia smart phones using Maas360 • VMWare \ VSphere •

#### Service Desk Analyst (2nd Line)

January 2011 - August 2015

**RX Systems** 

Second line technical support for independent and group pharmacies across the UK and Northern Ireland • Logging and taking ownership of calls through to completion • Pharmaceutical software (Proscript, ProManager) support and training • Windows operating systems and Outlook support, troubleshooting and configuration • Hardware support (label printers, prescription endorsing printers, desktop and network printers) • Booking engineers for hardware replacements or repairs • Troubleshooting, repairing and configuring networks, routers and switches • Reporting internet outages to service providers through to complete resolution • Supervising and training new staff and customers

**Temporary Role** 

IPSOS-MORI UK

Working on various projects within the Coding Department • Data analyst

**Sales Assistant** 

July 2008 - June 2009

October 2009 - Sep 2010

Jessops

Providing sales and general advice to customers, with regards to cameras, photographic equipment and accessories Assisting customers on the Photo Kiosks • Ensuring all price change, stock recall and merchandising requests from Head Office are implemented within the given deadlines • Receiving deliveries, repairs and stock checking • Maintaining the cleanliness of shop floor and cabinets • Checking all items are fully stocked

### **Helpdesk Controller**

April 2001 - February 2008

IPSOS-MORI UK

Second line technical support for approximately 1300 external users across the UK and internal staff • Troubleshooting, logging and taking ownership of calls • Supporting staff remotely, via VNC • Servicing, repairing and testing laptops, PC's and equipment • Updating and Ghosting laptop builds • Configuring wireless and local area connections on laptops or PC's • Creating and maintaining the department's website documenting office procedures • Reviewing and updating user instructions, including manuals and specific project information • Monitoring Windows 2000 server activity and ensuring essential SQL processes are always running • Setting up surveys on our Field Management database so they are ready for the users to download • Creating and distributing cd's/zip disks/usb keys containing multimedia files for use with relevant scripts • Using Unix to clean and re-format any corrupt data and tracing missing data • Maintaining stock levels of replaceable items for laptops • Arranging collections and deliveries of replacement equipment or machines • Responding to general e-mails and queries • Ensuring the smooth running of the department in my manager's absence.

#### **Administration Officer / Employment & Training Adviser**

August 1994 - March 2001

Lifetime Careers Ltd (Harrow Careers Service, London Borough of Harrow)

Interviewing clients for job and training opportunities • Liaising with Employers, Job Centres and Training Providers on a regular basis • Maintaining and updating the client database • Helping members of the public with general enquiries, careers advice and course information • Other duties included word-processing letters, memorandums and documents Desktop publishing posters, OHT's and forms for use internally and externally • Designing workbooks and presentations for staff to use in schools • Reception and telephone duties and ordering stationery and monitoring stock levels.

## **Education**

**College of Northwest London** 

April 2013

ITIL Foundation

Harrow College, Harrow On The Hill

Harrow College, Harrow On The Hill

Intermediate Photography

University of Westminster, Harrow

Macromedia Flash 8

November 2003 - April 2004

December 2007

September 2009 - January 2010

Computer Maintenance and OCR Installation Certificate Level 2 (A+)

College of North West London, Willesden September 2001 - May 2002

Internet Web Design Credit Certificate Level 2

Harrow College, Harrow Weald January 2000 - April 2000

PC Upgrade and Maintenance

**Greenhill College, Harrow** September 1993 - July 1995

NVQ Business Administration Level I, 2 and 3.

RSA Typing Level 1

Park High School, Stanmore September 1988 - June 1992

GCSF:

**English Literature** Grade B Information Technology Grade C English Language Grade B **Business Studies** Grade C **English Oral** Mathematics Grade C

### References

Available on request